Hello, friends.
That was sad so let me just share a little bit of information that's very important you understand
that the people who are requiring this recorded.
Don't hear you very well?
And, I've been watching some videos of myself and
...hunter and it looks really sad because wilt
...make something we'll say something very...great pithy something very wise as we do
...then it looks like it doesn't land.
we need to be louder so that we don't look like idiots in the recorded version.
Homo all moi.
...think...going to my wife that part.
I am...handsome in this is my bosco hunter and we are the lesser scott's.
And, we are here to talk about the introduction to sp net five.
And, I want to point out this is part one of to part
...is tomorrow morning at nine with damian edwards is going to do a deep divx so
if we're going to be kind of one hundred and into joiner level here and then we get to
damning we're just going to keep going off into the sky where
...a big breath thing they were going across a lot of topics in not go super deepening those topics
...and tamar...go super deep and a couple topics.
Okay, so, do make sure that you take a picture of this q r code and
...for posterity for the future...uses q r codes?
...today.
So, this is all about sp dot net five the modern
web and why we made this before we even get into...five let's you're going to go right to
...let's talk about first of anybody's...
We just ship via twenty fifteen rc yesterday for you guys.
Asp...five is not rc is if
...play with you'll see it says beta for and that's because we are a little bit behind
the via schedule so we expect I don't know when they're in our team but I know we're in
our tm basically one update behind them so whenever bs
...m will do and,
our team about two or three months after that said we know a lot of folks are building web
...today and even if you're not...five and you're still usingin the
cfive.
With api to signal...three web forms there's a bunch of updates in the
ftwenty fifteen rc that effect you guys
as well and we're...to scroll through and show a couple these is a blog post up on
...web the blog...you go there you can read all these changes there's some bugs in
...twenty fifteen rc imagine that there's work-arounds for the bugs in this blog post as
well as the biggest thing is we did
...support so even if you using web forms are in the cfive.
...api to you get all the new csharp all-new vb features this is
actually really cool here's a blurry screenshot here this is a
web forms page...seven there is using a new roslyn.
Csharp language feature so there are cool
and interesting stuff happening web form...got a sank model pining with
...all the http to...running on system web which are
...cfive jan and search they get ...they get
...should be to supports, yeah,actually...model...for web forms so anybody...building
...the current...there is love for those bits in this release don't forget that as well and we do know
that's a little bit confusing that it feels like the number five is a greater number
than four-point-six but it is a parallel track it's the difference
in for framework and the core framework we'll talk about those differences as we get into little more
detail but I just...make us understand that it's been a four-six kind of makes the world
...as a lot of really cool stuff happening so, this is happening in parallel right.
Okay, let's talk about asking at five ...I don't...of...today we have lots of demos and we...a lot of
time on slides...you want to talk about some of the design
...but a around estimate five one of them is we totally modular we build
...dot net back in the day the idea there was...the kitchen-sink in here
and have every feature turned on by default because we're trying to bring web developers from
our desktop developers into web and we would make a simple
as possible now we move for the future and now we...make web apps as fast as
...so now you can turn on our office
...you want and will show that the demos another thing is...network for the cloud and,
microsoft and we...make it even easier...to take
...application in publisher to add your inhabit work when you use
features like scale-up and scale down and stuff like that so there's some sort of changes in the framework to do
you with this faster development cycle on my machine building and
...five app...a web forms app
...change and recompile and stuff is like a second cycle?
We've got that down to two seconds right now on estimate five and we think we maybe can even
those...the future I'm going to...everybody my laptop has been head every version visual studio
...for like the last six months...fast even with...five
...couple generations old but if you download the rc you should see the two-second thing that we're talking
about right cross-platform so...you can buildings pfive application you can run it on
windows mac and linux because of that that's why you see this choose your editors
and tools above so one of the things we're going to show today a little bit of an essential lot more
on friday is pretty much anything
you can do in visual studio we have a way to do on command-line and that's because if you're on a
...linux machine there is no visual studio...code we just announced yesterday right but,
it's an editor and this will cause a lot of ...a confusion consternation where people will say hey I like
visual studio code winning...this fancy new visual studio feature in visual studio code
missing the point if you ask those kinda questions...not going to...any visual designers
in visual studio code if you want to know how to do this thing in visual coding
to the command-line because that's who that's for but if you are and id person you're going
to the id and this features that we're going to show you were going to spend some time in text files
doing things the command-line for all of those things there is also a gesture a
ui gesture within the studio so he might prefer to go to the command-line and type,
you know, restore whatever someone else might refer prefer to write click on something and
solution explore into the same gesture but the essence is the same so we're going
to show you the ui layer and then what's underneath and the nice thing of
...that there's no black boxes anymore right we're not going to take the visual...oop that...be a
...actually that's pretty I would hate to call it text studio it's not quite
as cool command-line studio command-line studio the other thing is we want we want arithmetic
the fast is it possibly can be so there's a lot of work has been done in
...five to make it super-fast and scale a lot more...today so, for example,
...estimate five application...ninety percent less memory than a existing...
application today and, that's because we stripped a bunch of stuff out and...bunch of stuff to the point that we
are comparably or better than no js and in many
...situations now so that's kind of core tenets on is it five okay and,
then are ... is a share final slide that nice we are five minutes in we
are last slide is a developer conference after all there's actually a person from a popular news
site who was complaining about all the code that was being showed in the keynote?
Thank you...here you on the tape yeah,
I mean this is a developer conference this next year we're going to put on the microsoft powerpoint conference just for those people that.
Yes,
so, these circle parts in yellow are the parts of asp net and,
dot net...open-source and there are more than there are not all of the jitter
all the compilers all the core...dot...core framework itself is
...net...parts four and five
...signal are all open-source you notice the pieces that aren't are some of
...pieces the pieces chip with windows the pieces for which there are no good reasons for them to get the
open-source even the ones...circled the source code is available like
...four-point-six for all of us spatially you can get these source its source open right reference
source...the reason there is we did open-source code and put a lot...source code for
dot net four-six up and get up the challenges we can't really think
...contribution because if you change anything that framework something breaks somewhere and,
you know, you guys all the rumah probably got,
you know, a for five-one or for five-two...feature head against the wall and
in work and that's why we don't take changes on that thing and that's actually a really great point for why
we've architected this the way it is that you want to be able to take application a and put on a machine and
...and someone else another apartment makes app be you don't want to have
...we don't have dot...for five-two on that machine we have four
...were afraid to take this that goes away happy and app bacon
live together with their own private builds of the
...in framework private builds of whatever they like.
So, let's switch over and that's...
The aso a pretty exciting announcements announcement here this is a new site we have
called asp net dot...studies business...fancier your
...just...canada how do I use the use a...use this...the...
Only manages use the...on this thing attract pad is terrible.
This is doctor sp net and this is powered by read the
...which is stinks.
Based mark down style restructured text
continuous integration for...doctor and get up not cool check this out.
Say now your first application amac.
Lovely...and then at the bottom fork these...
write the check this out click on the version of the...
I want to...or I want to epub want to read the kindle.
Click on pbs and now you're bringing down the
...and when the changes get made in get hub that automatically...flows through so we're given that a
try, yeah, once we feel is totally out we actually plan to publish those
...ourselves on some of the stores yet and we're going to...
Check it out nice.
All right much blank pages.
Nice there.
That pages intentionally left length.
All books start with...idling pages I don't know why kill trees.
...a big it's big tree lobby.
As we were saying earlier ...at five is
modular so this is what the minimal estimate application looks like today...
is hello world this is hello world and this looks like very similar to something that you would see in something like
...js now this isn't file new project default app this is empty
...boundary project empty application ok so this is a difference between the one...get bootstrap
...this is...now the difference between doing this and opening up web forms and going
into default spx and typing response dot write line hello world is what sir.
...because you never listen to me course not the difference between this
here and...default spx and saying response that right hello world yeah,
and, if you're doing default...in spx were in dc or any
those kinds of things there's a whole pile of modules are going to run inside of
...layers between un hello world layers for good reason
...the important thing when you hear that something is
improved in performance by to hundred-percent that doesn't mean that it
sucked hundred-percent before and we just found something
...literally trying to understand the difference between how do you build a mini-van which is extremely useful for caring
kids and groceries around and how do you build a motorcycle but use the same core concepts
we wanted to make...that five both of those things so you could...anything you want here
and, this is when you see some of these synthetic benchmarks against net and they're comparing,
you know, we're running modules who running routing we're running error pages
...bring all that technology...hello world
guess what we're going to slow right you can't benchmark node and web forms if node all they do is
handler...world and just kind of...eye-hand...as a lower?
This would be what you would compare but if but even that this
...handler, handler still going to have all that other stuff happen so you have basically nothing
right I have nothing so this would be this will give me a yells going to death right so normally you would get a nice air page
...if you're in this in a...much lower-level...page when I run this okay.
White.
you get basically a stack up and...that come from that came from our web post
okay from the host...this is the thing that holds the whole thing togetherboots the stack up said
hey the app blew up in my face okay here's...here's what I put out now
...interesting if you actually want a nice airbases show how modular we are let me-let me
jumping down here and...page.
...while he's doing that he could go to references
and add reference or add new get.
But, those references are there on the left-hand side so that's an example of there's the
...gesture...the text gesture
usual makes you happy the result is the same notice that when he type that diagnostics
...appeared on the right-hand side if you had done that with the ui gesture it-would appeared in the text
file make sense.
So, now I've got an emphasis use era page so basically enabled and air page
...the application...
...not ship with their page now we get a
sang on and you've got a bunch of stuff in here.
That doesn't do anything.
This is an empty app always...app there's
...doesn't have anything there's not much in thisthose a light up as we start filling up...stuff right but,
this is a nice change that you can not change replaces your page which you never could have
done before because there's no way to recompile system web and replace...a pipeline,
pipeline nice another fun thing to show here as well is now
that you describe this folder that we have new folder called the brute, yeah, this is a really interesting one when
nbc came out people who are web for people get freaked out because you go ahead slash
home slash index and they go looking for that on-disk?
And, this was actually a weakness
of web forms developers about ten fifteen years ago because what would happen as we go to other frameworks and we'd
go looking for stuff because we thought there was a direct relationship between the url
...disk...move forward into a
new world where you've got javascript libraries that you bring in the need to be squares
...needs to be mystified there is now a difference between the code that you look at
and the resulting build of your application so www
...is now if folder a place that lives under your app that's where static
stuff is served out of so if you want to serve foo dot html you don't drop it in the
root of your project you drop it in...root the value that
provides is that I can add a bunch of javascript libraries doesn't automatically make them accessible
to my application they get accessible...my app when I copy them into
wwe route which means I...have the unmanned fide versions out my can be looking at them and then I can go
and post-process them and drop them in there so what if you denser so what
...new now is I added
go back to visual studio I added a hello that html file
...application you have hello dot html so he put that inside that we're.
Okay, so, then.
Does it get serve when you ask for and then we're going to do is going to ask for that okay?
Do not get served...said hello html?
you basically my app spits out hello world no matter no matter what so
...the handler, handler those learning last the last
...anything you want there just like...and then it was work.
Yes, archetype...webbing that's what types to happens,
you know,...allstate catches everything but the point the
point there is we don't even serve static files...don't included error page and
...on included static file handler that is innovation.
...the point here is...cafeteria plan
you get exactly what you want no more than you ask for so this
...absolute control I just added static files back home.
And, I'll come over here and this now see app
...positive for a second please...this out because this whole use thing is
confusing you see those arrows are pointing down those are extension methods
we added that static file thing in there is now use static files it's not
that you have to memorize a whole bunch of use this and use that kind of stuff as you add new
packages you go and let's say someone
makes the open-source way better version of the...screen of death.
He'll just swap out his version swap that went in and then he'll
use their extension method and that added into the pipeline that's how that appeared there.
So, can we serve html...new strangled
...things there you go hello from the build...even better when it's big farm?
So, I just showing you we're now modular you can turn on or off all
of our features as much as you want.
So, now let's go and create a...app like an actual default
...here and this is also an interesting point
...he makes is this new app there's a difference between a web forms app...
session cookie management and all those kinds of things...nbc app...multiple layers and
are very low-level tiny maybe and io t scenario where you've got...serving
jason you're doing that directly or something in between with web api we want you to
be able to do those little scenarios and the big scenarios
and because you can pick the pieces that you want you're going to get the perf you're never going to be asking yourself a
question like what's in between me and the wire?
Some saying.
Abstraction layers can get you in trouble
you add too many layers of abstraction and we hit a lot of stuff and web forms and that's
okay because it's a powerful framework for putting together compose will apps but we
hit them because dragging a button on to design surface and making it button click was an
important scenario important scenario but now we're in a new world right what the key
to into the new world because we now don't require visual
...is we do all of our compilation inside of our inside race net
...compile itself so in this scenario
...modify this...get the page appear your application description page share
...say hello...has to be clear this is not...your in...csharp code
okay you haven't typed control I'm not I'm not saved anything at all don't trick them and on your machine
...two seconds on my machine it'll take like six seconds and that's because if you
...too much junk on...so...point here is we're now building.
...and what's cool that is...roslyn to do this and what the
perfect proves we have is when we compile now we no longer
...when you make a change you save some csharp
disk then you loaded back up into the compiler than the compiler saves
...back to disk and you pick...dl up and then you run...right that's just how the
circle life works when compile in this world?
You save the textile the disk you redid up and you compile...in memory and the assembly always
stays in memory it sits there nothing ever got emitted to disk that said we know that when people
publisher applications they want to be able to pre-compressor elements and put them up as well right we
...to do...been solder here is there been folder I don't know-how to use the number and here.
Is there...where did you put the...the deal?
With dealers.
Darn you hunter so there's no been and there's no
option is no dealer because when you do things in node
a ruby your python with these interpreted languages types encoding it refresh types
...hip fresh but there's value and there's our in the clr
...in csharp and...so you want to have those kinds of
statically type languages how do you get the feeling of a dynamic language that...you know,
just refresh, refresh, refresh but also this speed in the our of net you do that with
roslyn right next is references if you look at references here is not got these
the to nipped references to these two frameworks we have whom
...dn x which is dot net execution done...execution
environment...and we have one for four-point-five one and we have which will run
...four-point-five, four-point-five to four...so you are actually compiling this for two different frameworks
right now correct okay this is kind of like with universe...for this
compile for that your compiling simultaneously for dot net full framework and
...and dot net core right and now packages show up in references,
you know, five years...according to get packages
...now first-class this is a really important point asp dot net five
works on both frameworks it's not too different versions of sp net
...runs on a full framework runs in the core framework you then target them both
and if you use something that's in the course
clr it will warn you and you can decide if you want to ff around that.
But, if you look like in the framework searching a
...dependency graphic I look there's that one's a new get package and that one must be local yes or
...system or part ok so in the...it's actually part of we framework.
I like...version number show too.
That's cool.
So, that's a new concepts okay.
...the hang actually
...going project...from actually as we're going next let's look at frameworks real quick.
...cs project...so
...with cs proj right which is the csharp project file you would have these
includes and you'd say I want to add foo dot cs and you're going to...cs
progeny you add the food out cs in large teams...be a constant merge issue
as people add-in removes stuff so we're switching to a format where if it's in the folder
it's in the project okay if you don't want
their we've inverted it so now you would exclude that right out of the project
...so we're showing all the packages that we require for this application
to run right here and this is a declaration in the project...of what we want.
And, then what's in the references is what we got
right and we planned actually replace packages that can fig across the projects
...project adjacent future as well that's coming something else we have years we have commands,
yeah, this was this...me a while you my head around because this is a very.
Generic and open way to do things but initially I thought I was just a way to start the web server bcs get
commands...name value name value the name can be anything you want doesn't have to
...letters he in their that case...web instead...and then the...the
...on the other side there is actually a type name.
And, you could have your own commands so then you would go and say, you know,
generate code or run this
a generic commander task you might want to run that wasn't being handle
...you by a...and we'll talk about those so here he's got the entity framework stuff he's got a
...got web which runs in this case the...net web
server but when we look at this on another platform we might use a different web server and we would tape
...dn x fool where fu was some custom thing
it's a very extensible way to do...to run that command I run the dynamics cuter
give it to a dot...the current directory and I told...command...I want to run so I want to run
web which point I'm going to launch the web browser or what's okay so just to be clear has the fonts
...kind of sm...what you've done is your in the same folder in the
...folder their of the...the project jason lives correct yes
project adjacent location see...appear as you have to put the dot there
...put a path to where your project is you put it on the anywhere
okay and then web the companion run command you want to in this case where web
then web if I look...the task explore the task manager
...x being their living as the component container and then it will have instantiated
...hosting part of the web listener to be doing that now by copy this exact
project file...amac and said dn x web it would fail right
...there will if you notice this is says microsoft that cannot
...that web listener web designer...weblets web listeners basically
deal we wrote the talked http...and hp systems and exist on the
mac so we have a another one of these we written called pastoral and...the one we run a
mac and it will do the same operation ...using live uyvy...you ve is what
...with the...the underlying stack that makes the node...web server work.
So,...of actually frameworks are...talk about framework
...the bottom of...the parallel I...as you see
...is dn x for five-one indian x core five you see on the right-hand side
...references can-you delete the dn x four five one-liner.
...you...for snacks...
So, kind of diabetic or some these are looking for snacks.
Look,...to say.
You see how it's banged out right now...right there.
That's back did a new get restore.
To make sure that...had all the things...them all up.
So, talk...
Okay, let's talk about our so you know-how you've got imis build...builds within
...you used to build stuff on the server-side other web frameworks in a lot of open-source people in front-end web
developers use client-side frameworks they have client-side bills they have
client-side tools they have library managers new gets and things like that except they have
things like bauer...pm and bauer brings down libraries and, pm brings
...libraries and tools that's all integrated into this now as
well that means that if you see some cool thing that the node kids are using
you want that to you can have that you might ask why we're use what why we bring
bauer into individual studio ...we have new get already because the
whole world uses it right today what happens is a lot of people a lot of us inside
of inside microsoft a lot of people deportees net have gone out to
bauer grab scripts from their...up...new get packages wrangler is and,
then we try to maintain...and maintain these things right but the
realities are always out-of-date so we said why keep being out-of-date let's go to the source so
two-story who do you think handles the angular packages a new get for the angular javascript library.
...popper and why...jump up and do it
...get sick of it recall means...would you do it and then I got sick of it and I
ask another guy and it's stupid because we're always behind
...happens three hours after the next version of anger comes out
...me why you now have angular on new get?
Wintertime tournaments so,
this like we showed in...you can see here we get full intelligence so we're not in the project updates anymore we're in the
bauer and I've selected angular js and is saying what version do I want
...like latest version I
...press save now that does not bring angular into my
projects it makes it available to my project but
member that www route gotta get over there someone has
to put it there it doesn't just drop it into the root of my direct of my system
...in new get one of the first things people wanted was the ability to control
where the javascript scope now you get that so, yeah,
we...folder...we have another file which is a goal filed
...which...copy this to your...folder right so we've got brunt
and gulp which are client-side microsoft builds their build systems are task
managers gulp is the one that's hot right now and then you would in your...task change it so that it
copy that angular into the root or whatever you wanted to be because everyone's puts their
script somewhere else what is a two-step process will try to make that as easy as we can so...
stuff injuring as well so we have a new feature and, just...called the task...explore tr easily
...inside the team and the idea here was historically we've done things like
...do something that goes in lengths your javascript that means is going to look for common javascript...or look
at your css...common css...we've taken the open-source things that are out there
we written our own to replace those...of tool them...visual studio right so
...you want to run js lent as part of your build what you've got here is a binding
between events that happen in visual studio and events that exist...task that
...is in your profile so-if you want-to modifier css before...build
...put that in your go file you added to before build right so we're no longer trying to keep up with these
open-source libraries...building in you don't have to see this stuff the stuff all...most developers you
...on your application...and stuff is going to be running behind-the-scene you might say that's a lot of concepts
to learn hundred-mile new project is going...do the right thing by default will have a good nice
...you can just use...to think about it so one final thing I want
to shown this application right now is I want to go to properties?
And, inside my properties...notice I have this option where I can say I want to use a dn
x zoom in on the and let's zoom in here.
So, wits version of this execution environment
...you want to use...do this in the for framework...do this and dot net core.
...we have...to a specific version member we said before about how you've got a machine
that's got a dot net whatever on it and application a I want to application
...we cannot risk those applications breaking each other they have to be
in their own universe so we're just like core here
...now we're basically told when I build I want to...build this
thing for the core framework which I want let's have that full side-by-side.
Just build and make sure...still healthy ok, and,...to a public
...funny story when he actually is pressing...actually do anything it just
does like spell-check it doesn't have to loaded...doesn't have to load all the errors in your in your
...window who...there's no deal elegant made...packed up and bundle it...that is
...the actual dls happen he's going to go into a publish to a file system
...a published this onto a usb
...and...publicity like folder might...okay so what is
to see back maybe foo-foo z colon and I think they added that.
Put in foo-foo...has lots of...that's good.
All right so what this will do is actually...you're doing that let's
...look at happen more fun to see it happen.
Didn't ...app...appeared?
Some stuff going by.
...that where do you think those three things came from the all.
Those are the commands from project adjacent so, can...laptop what...
...like as a...
Always one of the once you
...for free...so nice thank you for give-me...like open up seriously.
What kind of va thing
...using these days get tv port and?
...full-size hci.
Okay,...anything here...
Clear my browser history before you put that onstage measure handsome
...copying this onto his well on
...us speakeasy here okay so he's publishing
to this location and then what I'm going to do...that?
And, that's...important...that's not
...that that's network...the...tiny deviate with this
...copying...you never know...done all right I can't see the screen catch...screen.
By broke that moi.
...mail now.
Slows...slows...who brings...low memory stick to develop a conference.
One of the...earlier was.
Hanging on it...about ninety...about...notes about.
It's about two hours and.
Because the best part about windows eight is that dialogue
...saying this is like yes disappointments.
Too bad they can't see the disappointment.
...is when this case we actually compile that is an application against dot net core
for like five minutes and because dot net core is on this means the application can run
on any machine without affecting that machine...all the
application doesn't touch system thirty-two it doesn't such registry doesn't touch anything on
the machine at all you install anything on...visual studio like.
...code but not any you have you don't have any...new bits...yet.
...nothing on here.
Any britney spears fell down.
It's going to read about that real quick average...an ios game or something...
So,...just run that web command.
And, did you didn't have the consul...info
...act forget to turn the consul longer on...debug?
Your...you...do I...example.
Oxygen your the busts...pardon me five...
It really is running optimistic is not touching local drive at all is running that is
a website running off his memory stick now I'm going to pull the memory sick-out without
warning the operating system because life is too short to safely remove your...
Thank you...I don't know what's going to happen now as...screens going.
Not happy.
...show one more concept here and this is the notion of what we call environment's
...twenty minutes where you need to...related google facile faster
...my project again and if I come over here
...properties are going to debug there's this notion of
And, that's...you said if you want to have...I doing a development build my doing a staging build
brand is that a magic string for development...development called...I mean it's
a hash tags you could change that you can to development whatever word you want so dev test staging,
staging one staging to I can make those things up myself, yeah, so, that's why do we care about this let's
look at the views and let's go look inside of shared and let's look at the layout file
ok now...either master page this is showing some stuff which...is going tomorrow...
more detail iraqi doing dependency injection here and actually injecting some types and stuff directly
to the page...here look we have this new thing senses environment
names equals development environment names equal staging is done see how that's
in purple that's actually not html tag that will get admitted it's just letting us know that if we are
in development drop in those style sheets and if you are in either staging
...production use these other ones will actually not even more than use the other ones you look at these other ones
they're interesting because they actually point-two.
Version of the scripts on a on a...a...interesting so
you've got bootstrap coming out of a specific folder locally and then in production use which over
...the assyrian but well even better the look we have a...fallback that...means if the
...in is not available will fallback your local system.
This is an we have a feature called heck helpers thank you.
So, we have this new feature which they're going to go into deep on friday which is an awesome feature called tag helpers
and, that's these tags...so even like link what happens if I put any of
these asp dashes in there that tells it that we don't want to use the html link we want use
the special version we have over written that understands...dash fallback that each
...right so much easier way than going writing all of that's how that works
...show one more example of tag helpers which is pretty good pretty cool I'm going to go in here
login and look at the login file all right so...login file and
first-run the app to some people...like a login page and pretty...people
...look like okay...I'm guessing it will have a username or password...xbox in
a button that says login just...you re my mind just guessing?
Redman that was worth the time ok so.
So, if you look at this page.
We didn't write html dot text box anywhere on here
right we just wrote html.
So, these are...inputs input tags regular input tag but because it
has this asp dash for that enables the html helper or the
...written for this that understands these things and actually does the equivalent of html that
...right now if I'd...do this before you got to go like
...html dot text box right those helpers the problem with early parts of
raiser it felt weird is you switch back and forth between html and
...trying to keep you in html more often
...I see any actually csharp in here except for what you're doing right now...yeah,
...be the old way this is the old way which
was pretty stupid about ang on now it was pretty awesome at the time knows terrible this is this
...a we screwed up really bad so.
...look at this we have this awesome editor that has awesome css intelligence it's not going to
understand what new curly brace quote class equals...not in html
...one...all the intelligence so,
that was a bad idea we started using angular and stuff with our at
...bootstrap and I would be a little more measured sir.
And, these before all the features that you expect.
Exist here before knows the model
...my page is...me all the intelligence so
...html tag what happens is as soon as I type quotes I'm actually not
...tag anymore I'm actually in csharp and you got that injected in there because the whole page knows about that
rice's for that model tomorrow in the in...deep dive demeans
...come on, stage and show you how these things work show you how to write and yourself and,
they're pretty cool so let's.
Undo any...here that will not compile.
And, let's see we want to next.
Configuration we've only got eighteen minutes.
So, number okay if you're good so another thing we
talked about earlier we showed that empty application we showed...
had nothing turned on and now I'm actually looking at a full...application and now you can see
...booting up...configuration system as I scroll down you're going to see that I'm
going to boot-up the support for entity framework the support for identity
system you can see m in a boot-up some of the services required for
often kate authentication with facebook and I notice that in the configuration part you mention the
...thing do I have to use jason for...no you don't actually use this configuration what
...what if I and I files...how we role in my in my enterprise.
Remove just for handsome and he after that he's been begging us for five years
...the one feature hp that needs to succeed...final files.
Just respect the any man.
...the point there is that before doing things like...settings, you know,
it's angle brackets adding more and more stuff into your web
...this is an extensible configuration system that allows you to pulling...from wherever you
...wherever you have makes you happy wherever your company like well it also we're
...multiple layers you might notice...that I first
at adjacent file right then I come down here and say we had another visions outside another reason
...if you want to have a development version of your script values get rid of others transform
you're actually chaining them...be...dot jason nab can fig dot environment dot
jason and one would overwrite...one can override the other one and...notice...the very bottom here, yeah,
we have configure environment variables and we have this because we think if you're going to
...in the cloud you should have the conflict file it all the your production setting should be
handle your iq department control in the cloud right not by the
...if you've ever done anything with as...like me you accidentally checked in
...password or connection string or something like that into a web and fig and then it's
...how do you tell get that you didn't really mean it.
You know, and, intel give...that you didn't really mean I guess
...all changing our passwords with this you can have a configuration locally you can have it then
...environment variable...configuration and he's got a another configuration that's environment specific and
then can override those with environment variables which are set outside of your code?
More so is anybody this room and I ever checking to get hub any of your
connection streams are definitely...actually this migrate whereas you and I know there's more than
...search give hub for the word password.
Yeah, you find a few so you'll notice
if I'm in my development environment which means I'm right where I'm in now we had another one your called
ad user...so the idea is we built a featured ask net where you never ever put your
connection strings inside of the folder structure here which means you never
had the chance of accidentally get pushing it up your server
nice so thank you.
So, what I would do is I would run this new command we have called user secret?
...user secret that is yet another command-line thing for me to learn another
...will have institute feeling for this as well but is an actual command-line
is something that you're going to describe explain how to write tomorrow this is actually a is one of the
...net five consul lap who are dn x consul lab that's
installed my path remember how we had all those commands in project jason your dot
execution environment can have commands as well so this is actually one of those you can make your
own this is not going to go learn a whole pile of these you can write your own so what I'm going
to do here is I'm going to say app settings that site title.
And, I can say that's just...magic string app settings outside
...also...I'm like that from...in rand-r project, project configuring okay.
So, what that does is academic...here and say, you know,
list my...using like dp api or what
...secret places this I'm not going to tell you what that's not really...to find out...looking
...coding get hub and find out where it actually...what we typically do is we recommend you put connection strings
...with this tool and what this tool actually does is it puts it puts those
things inside of your user folder that's not very secret well it's not your project which means not...go to get
...that's actually that's the only care about is we don't want
...stuff stored in your project so it goes to get...
And, I should be able to come down here in the application and pull
that back out...jump ahead yes in the interest of time if the client list of
...we've got about fourteen minutes.
When you that one of that one...need to do all these things here?
...other six pages let's do controllers...furs us do that
...simpler evolutionary and then...and we'll jump...that are
ok so the unwind a few things here...straighten back out that's been my
...folder and let's go add a new comptroller so before
there was adding controllers and driving them from controller or deriving from api
controller and we unify those...now you've got an nbc controller in a web api
...the same thing but sometimes still people don't necessarily want to have a
controller base class where they want to comptroller less controller.
What they want I don't know?
...doesn't that kind of a...confidences you run the team.
So, the point of this example is we were saying earlier that a
...modular and getting...opt into how much stuff that you want right...you don't want our control
...class today you can do a bunch of voodoo...to work around that in the new
world you can use is mushers little nbc's you want here I've got a simple class
called scott controller it has index method return string
...this is from my controller that is there is a pogo class plain old clr object.
Now does that mean that I can go and
start randomly calling functions on public classes and that would be a bad thing.
Conditions so that only...only works
...wide-screen this only works because I'm my name is scott
controller so by convened always done
is nbc's always work this way where it implies this okay because the name ended in
...correct so that I'm going to login to like, you know,
someone's company and hope that they have things that are name controller.
The office of the...probably a good place to start.
Appoint about this is I could actually
...controllerbase class of wanted-to here.
I don't even have to we use dependency injection is built-in feature inside...can at
...so everything is being depends injected in here if I want to go grab any the things
...controller their typically being dependency injection if you go the source code for the new comptroller
based class all it does have a constructor that takes all the things are being brought in by dependency injection
...indigo new comptroller today you say this dot and there's all this great stuff that's available in
...bags and action results and all those kinds of things here
you're on your own right but no it's being injected in by the by the system
an example of that is notice here I've got this longer factory that we addconsul logging on
...set by default...warning...wants to be a situ...if I look at this is returning
it it's using I longer factory right I could take...I
...factory make that constructor on my
...this controller ik so my pogo...there my plane all object there I could say
...a constructor for it takes and I longer factory and they will automatically end up in there and I can
squirrel when use correct I'm not going to do it but which exact make sense all right good like that so we have been
suggestion built-in wellness also want to say if you want to
use your own thing yep we support all the popular
gis exist today phrase net already we options within the work so you don't have to use
our thing but we don't require one of those to go so
...talked about the concept of dn...and we've seen as dot net execution virus
...briefly the command-line and I'm going to after insist that you zoom in on.
...go so the dot net version managerthe dn
...as a command-line that's going to allow you to
come manage all these different frameworks because we anticipate a world where there's going to be, you know, four or five
these different ones and you're going to be testing on one as you develop actively on another or maybe someone
finds a bug in the course...they want to change it
...make their own private build-up that or you're going to have you know,
mono might be one...the course are might be another and you're going to move around dn
gm will list those...he can...vm space
list and see them he actually has for versions there right actually they're one for each
...course clr and then if he went and installed a new one like beta three
...five those are going to show up there and notice where they live they live not and
Know system thirty-two.
Live-in as user folder
...go I can go I've got a ...open...use my user folder here I've...this...called dn x
...of the...actually don't mind you see...default their.
Here yet I using this is really cool this is one of those things like, you know, when we keep we keep saying there's no black
boxes no black box...says default and one of those...active...
A default...is me at home and like...alias default that about
...secrets alias what's that
I found it default how do they keep track.
Magic the black box so I could
...trial-and-error called foo dot text and put the name
of a dn x in there and then go dn x use...a work.
Is sometimes the simplest thing works the same thing is all that way all these
runtime zer in my dn x runtime folder yep...delete, delete
...these...machine these are all this in their own folded by themselves full control?
So, let's sword you that knock over here
...I think is that button slashing.
Thinking announce here.
Okay.
Okay, so, I want...now you have eight minutes
fun...yoast net and why do this...you explain what
yoko is and what this is doing so there's no file new project amac there's no visual studio
...amac at but there's a thing called yeoman and yeoman is a template in generators
founding project for front-end web developers node folks do this and
...make their own generators there's one called
asp net generator that you can install once you've got yeoman and you type...like
...to get a series of generator choices you can pick from the nancy
asp that open-source framework or from...empty app or
...app and then he types...you there...I did here is I went folder
...what are the folder looks like it is now and I'll say restore the...you restore
...you dot net utility...basically a new get restore
...ok that's going out and then in that he says new
restore it restores not just the it basically everything that needs the
...pm the our of...new get and now he's in visual studio code and
we'll go into the web application folder here still going that's okay I'm going to
...here okay and you see this little fire here in the corn lower left corner which
is one project click on that?
That found the project dot jason that little fire represents on the
...which is an open-source project that knows about these things if you
...omni sharp dot net you can get in
...us sense on mac and linux for e-max them.
Brackets adam whatever makes you happy it comes with
visual studio code there's been a few people have ask questions about visual
...code and intelligence...csharp and stuff like that and we want to point out that right now for
visio code the intelligence for csharp is for asp net projects...or
...x projects and dn x consul projects you on the network apply why
...networking...spinning and...
The unplug the network was...this...important magnets.
I will fix it while you play with...kind of an ally but swap back...
Kind of...if now I what does this but.
We want to prove that it's modular that's fun and you can play you can do fun things.
So, inherent samples.
...hello, what's it.
...and run that.
Bring up this web one of cool things about what we're doing...connect being open-source and with
dot net core being open-source is now people can do all kinds
of crazy stuff with our platforms we had somebody just last weekend.
Ports net core to freebie sd as an example of something
...communities done and scott's going to show you some crazy thing
...go here is asp dot net running on this raspberry
Now this is not a declaration of support for internet raspberry
...this is a declaration of this is a really cool hack
of a lightweight framework that we can start porting all sorts of interesting stuff in this case here on the raspberry
...arm device I'm using mono.
...continue to be able to plug these things in any way you want if I get a
build of the course...runs the...reply maybe I could swap it out and
with that dot net version manager you can see how I might potentially do something like that so in my
mind I'm imagining the our that I can be on a raspberry
...returning jason's...imagining like coyotes scenarios ramming return the
...of like the moisture content one of my wife's plants.
Right and then I can scale my application all the way up into asher...from sixty
...k the sixty-four
terabytes or whatever that's what I think is exciting about a modular asp dot net,
you know, it's little this-is just a hello world but I could certainly spin to jason talk to devices
dpi or whatever I don't know
...builds work in which builds don't I just know that this build worked so, it is definitely in a hacker
phase when you're doing crazy stuff like what I'm trying to accomplish here.
...over there.
...change one thing...okay.
The network is not like a slice distances simpler project okay.
So, he's on code on this...here.
You see that...sharp their and visual studio code found one project can
you type context dot...to this is just first
...like...a zero.
A dot icio so now do var.
That way you don't give a hint what it is.
...so a is an n right.
So, then you get into stuff so then go and do change...
Bar a equals...lists situ one then you'll get intelligence and not just auto complete
and all that setting...intelligence these things I also discussing earlier I
...to command-line...x dash pastoral because in this particular case I'm on a mac
I don't have http...now I've got the custer command showing up here.
And, that's...still using an hosting...goes to the right there the server is castro and
...uses...uyvy or lib of is fallow likes to call it
is also the guy who thinks the new get your called nutcase.
That's...that's not going to happen we're not going to let that happen
here's hello world running automatic with
With visio code so if you go up to...
Dot asp dot net you can go
and cr continues integration server that is running our
...regularly you can get involved you can go to get hub slash
asp net slash home you can find all of this stuff up at www dot
...basically...that the acinet slash...
next well and I actually to give a little bit of a plug for that if we go up to asp net
slashed v next one of the things that we've been doing is every?
Tuesday.
With us community
stand-up basically alive broadcast just like a stand-up
...stand-up fifteen twenty minutes of what happened that week in
not you-know-who blog what but literally what got checked in what worked what didn't
what tester failing what do we, you know, where we heading we've been doing this for twenty nine?
Different episode they're cool episodes you'll hear us talk about arguing about how we think...thing should be built
in which look like...we asked people on the status and gives...opinions we look at the...on the
...to videos yep sodefinitely get involved in
that every tuesday and there you go if you have it at...in fact I thought that
one okay we miss the logging stuff so tomorrow...guys cover log yes we did not cover how logging
works and how to plug the new logging subsystem into diagnostics a...make sure
...cover that tomorrow but we got everything else you want to cover so all right cool thank you all very much?